# Andrew (Howon) Kim

# **Computer Vision Engineer**

Austintown, OH howonkim@berkeley.edu 408-628-2000

I have diverse experience, ranging from building a startup from its inception to scaling it up and working in prominent companies. In my first six months at LG and GM, I greatly achieved the first prize in a worldwide data analysis competition and also received Golden Awards for my contributions to smart factory initiatives. My commitment to excellence and innovation drives my success in delivering impactful results.

#### **Education**

## University of California, Berkeley • Data Science • Berkeley, CA

12/2022

• Studied Computer Science and Data Science and graduated as Data Science: Applied Mathematics and Modeling.

# **Experience**

**Ultium Cells LLC** • Company of General Motors and LG Energy Solution

Computer Vision Engineer • Lordstown, OH

08/2023 - Present

- Developed statistical models using terabytes of manufacturing data and deep learning algorithms to detect defects.
- Awarded 1st Prize in a Global Data Analysis Competition by LG Energy Solution.
- Redesigned traditional manufacturing UI into a breakthrough interface, unprecedented in the industry.
- Possess a systematic understanding of advanced manufacturing systems, including PLC, SPC, and MES.

#### **Ultium Cells OEM •** LG Solution Partners

Computer Vision Engineer • Lordstown, OH

04/2023 - 08/2023

- Proficient in Python, C++, and WPF, delivering high-quality software solutions.
- Experienced with various camera systems and optical techniques, including Keyence, Cognex, and Basler.

#### **ReviewMe** • eBook Review Platform Startup

Lead Software Engineer • Seoul, Korea

09/2020 - 12/2021

- Researched deep learning model to evaluate concentration level with facial components for review system.
- Analyzed brain waves and facial components.
- Swift, SwiftUI, MLKit, ARKit, and Vision Framework.
- Patent for Kindle like review system and AI funds granted from government.

#### Samsung Electronics • Android Framework Department

Software Engineer • Suwon, Korea

06/2020 - 08/2020

- Researched machine learning project to automatically sort notifications in situational importance.
- Analyzed and optimized the Samsung frameworks written in Kotlin and Java.
- Experienced in Git, documentation, agile development, and led weekly intern sprint planning session.

#### **AltoyGames** • Game Studio Startup

Software Engineer and Co-Founder • Suwon, Korea

01/2020 - 06/2020

• Game development in Unity 3D and C#. Developed core components and algorithms from 2D to VR styled games.

#### **Volunteers**

#### Military Service • Republic of Korea Army

01/2012 - 10/2013

- Served as FDC at 25th DIV Field Artillery Division. Discharged as sergeant.
- Regiment commander award by saving suicide attempted soldier.

### **UC Berkeley Computer Science Tutor** • University of California at Berkeley

01/2019 - 05/2019

• Tutor of UC Berkeley's CS/DS courses with professional teaching class of CS370 (Introduction to Teaching Computer Science).

# Youth Leadership Camp Leader • Incheon Global Campus

01/2018

• Group facilitator at global conference for growing youth to develop their leadership skills as accomplishing the two projects deeply associated with UN SDGs.

#### **Unity 3D Developer** • Center for Creative Economy & Innovation

09/2017 - 12/2017

- Unity developer specialized in VR(Virtual Reality)/ AR(Augmented Reality) at Creative Innovative Center.
- Showcase: youtu.be/RhBANk3GCnE

#### **Technical Translator** • Rufus Software

07/2014 - 09/2014

• Translate technical manual of Rufus Software from English to Korean.

#### Public Relations Communications Officer • LG Display

01/2011 - 06/2011

• LG Display D'ple 2nd member, we organized media events, online advertisements, managed the social network.